cesarsway.com 2015-05-23

# Website Privacy Policy | Cesar Millan

This privacy policy describes the collection of information by Cesar Millan, Inc. (“CMI”, “we”, “us” or “our”) from users of our websites [www.cesarmillaninc.com](http://www.cesarmillaninc.com/ "www.cesarmillaninc.com") and [www.cesarsway.com](http://www.cesarsway.com/ "www.cesarsway.com") (collectively, the “Site”), and users of the various services we provide on the Site (collectively, the “Service”), as well as our use and disclosure of that information. By using the Site or any Service, you consent to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

### Personal Information

"Personal information," as used in this policy, is information that specifically identifies a person, such as a person's name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. Personal information also includes information about a person's activities, such as information about his or her activity on our Site or our Service, and demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, when any of this information is linked to personal information that identifies that person. Personal information does not include "aggregate" or other non-personally identifiable information. Aggregate information is information that we collect about a group or category of users that is not personally identifiable or from which individual identities are removed. We may use and disclose aggregate information, and other non-personally identifiable information, for various purposes, including but not limited to sharing with third parties aggregated demographic and statistical information.

### Collection of Information

#### Passive Information Collection

When you visit the Site or use our Service, some information is automatically collected, such as your computer's IP address, browser type, system type, the content and pages that you access on the Site or Service, "referring URL" (i.e., the page from which you navigated to the Site), the pages from which you navigate to and from the Site or Service, and the time you spend on the Site or the Service. We collect this information passively using technologies such as standard server logs, cookies, and clear GIFs. When you visit the Site, we may install a cookie on your computer. Cookies are small pieces of information that we place on your computer’s hard drive to enable you to more easily communicate and interact with the Site and for us to collect and record information related to your use of the Site.

We use passively-collected information to administer, operate, and improve our Site, our Service, and our other services and systems, and to provide services and content that are tailored to you. If we link or associate any information gathered through passive means with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information under this policy. Otherwise, we use information collected by passive means in non-personally identifiable form only.

Also, please be aware that third parties may set cookies on your hard drive or use other means of passively collecting information about your use of their services or content. We do not have access to, or control over, these third-party means of passive data collection.

#### Registration/Newsletter

If you choose to register on the Site, you are required to provide us with personally identifiable information, which may include your full name, address, telephone number and email address. If you post comments on the Site, you must first create a user name, and such user name will appear when your comments are posted. You may also choose to sign up for CMI’s newsletter. Signing up for the newsletter does not require registration. However, we will need to obtain your name and email address in order for you to subscribe to the newsletter. 

#### Purchases

When you make a purchase through the Site, you are required to provide us with personally identifiable information. This information may include your full name, your email address and method of payment, such as your credit card or debit card data, so that we may charge you for your purchases. We also will require information for the shipment of your order, which may include your address and telephone number, or the name, telephone number and delivery address of a third-party recipient of your order. We of course will use your personally identifiable information to charge or debit your accounts in payment for your purchases. We will forward certain of your personally identifiable information to delivery services and other third parties who process or deliver the products that you purchase from CMI, as needed for the processing or delivery of your order.

Placing an order through the Site automatically registers you on the Site.

We may offer various other ways for you to provide personal information to us voluntarily on our Site or our Service. For example, we may offer account registration (which, as stated above, is automatic when you make a purchase), the ability to create and maintain user profiles, the ability for you to participate in surveys or contests that we may provide, and the ability to post or share photographs, videos, and other content with other users of our Site and our Service. We also collect personal information when you request information about our services, request help or support, or otherwise communicate with us using contact forms or other methods for contacting us on our Site or our Service. We may collect personal information such as name, email address, city, state, country, other demographic information, interests and preferences, and personally identifying photographs and videos in these manners. 

#### Information from Other Sources

We may receive information about you, including personal information, from third parties, and may combine this information with other information we maintain about you. If we do so, this policy governs any combined information that we maintain in personally identifiable format.

### Use of Personal Information

We use personal information to provide services and information that you request; to enhance, improve, operate, and maintain our Site, our Service, and our other systems and resources; to prevent fraudulent use of our Site and our Service; to tailor your user experience; to maintain a record of our dealings with you, and for other administrative purposes.

We may also use personal information you provide to contact you regarding our products, services, and offers that we believe you may find of interest. We allow you to opt-out from receiving marketing communications from us as described in the “Choice” section below. 

### Disclosure of Information

We are not in the business of selling personal information about our users to third parties. We may disclose information about our users, including personal information, to third-party service providers (e.g., data storage and processing providers), that assist us in our work. We limit the personal information provided to these service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform their work for us.

We may also disclose information about our users, including personal information, if we believe that doing so is legally required or is in our interest to protect our property or other legal rights (including, but not limited to, enforcement of our agreements), or the rights or property of others.

As described below in the "Personal Information Available to Third Parties" section, personal information that you post or transmit to publicly-accessible areas of the Site or our Service, or to third-party services (each, a "Submission") may be available to third parties. 

In addition, information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets, or similar transaction, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, in which personal information could be transferred to third parties as one of our business assets.

### Personal Information Available to Third Parties 

Some features on our Site may allow you to post or submit personal information that is made available to other users of our Site and our Service, and to third-party services. If you post or submit information using these features, any personal information that you include with the post or submission will be made available to other users of our Site and our Service, as well as to any users of third-party services to which the post or submission is directed. Additionally, we may use personal information that you have otherwise provided to us in connection with certain types of content, such as photographs and videos, that you post on the Site or provide to us for possible display on the Site. You include personal information in any posts or submissions using such features at your sole risk.

We may allow you to select privacy options that limit access to some types of personal information that you post or submit using such features, but no security measures are impenetrable or perfect. Additionally, even in the event that information posted using such features may be removed, caching and archiving services may have saved that information, and other users or third parties may have copied or stored the information. We cannot warrant or guarantee that any personal information that you provide on and in connection with any such features will not be accessed, viewed, or used by unauthorized persons.

### Choice

If you receive marketing or promotional communications from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the message that we send. You may also opt-out from receiving marketing or promotional communications from us by sending us an email or by writing to us at the address given at the end of this policy. 

Additionally, if you do not wish to be notified by email, postal mail, telephone, or text messages regarding products, services, events, programs, and offers that we believe you may find of interest, you may opt-out from such communications by sending us an email or by writing to us at the address given at the end of this policy. Even if you opt-out from marketing and promotional communications, you may still receive messages regarding any accounts you maintain with us, and regarding important updates to our Site or our Service.

### Children

Children's safety is important to us, and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active interest in the online activities of their children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 without obtaining parental consent.

### International Visitors

This Site is generally intended for United States visitors. If you visit from other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please be aware that you are transferring personal information to the United States. The United States does not have the same data protection laws as some other regions. By providing personal information to us, you consent to the transfer of it to the United States and the use of it in accordance with this policy.

### Links

For your convenience, our Site may contain links to other Web sites, products, or services that we do not own or operate. If you choose to visit or use any third-party products or services, please be aware that this policy will not apply to your activities or any information you disclose while using third-party products or services or otherwise interacting with third parties.

For example, and without limitation, the Cesar Millan-branded services located at [www.sessionswithcesar.com](http://www.sessionswithcesar.com/ "www.sessionswithcesar.com") (including the “Sessions with Cesar” materials and the “Cesar Live” webinars), the “Cesar’s Pack” community/forums and all other materials available on such web pages: (i) are not operated by CMI and (ii) may be accessible from and provide links to other third-party websites and access to content, products and services of third parties. CMI is not responsible for examining or evaluating, and we do not warrant the offerings of, any of these (or other) third-party websites, and CMI does not assume any responsibility or liability for the actions, products, services or content of these or other third-party websites or any third parties. You should refer to the separate terms of use, privacy policies, and other rules posted on such websites before you use them.

### Security

We use reasonable security measures that are designed to protect information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Please note, however, that no data security measures can be guaranteed to be completely effective. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any personal information or other information. You transmit personal information to us at your own risk. We are not liable for the privacy of e-mail addresses, registration and identification information, communications, confidential or trade-secret information, or any other content stored on our equipment, transmitted over networks accessed by the Site, or otherwise connected with your use of our Service.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding the security of the Site, please e-mail [performance@cesarsway.com](mailto:performance@cesarsway.com).

If you suspect that you may have been a victim of fraud, we highly recommend you immediately take the appropriate steps to ensure your security. If you have further questions or concerns on this matter, please contact [reportfraud@cesarmillaninc.com](mailto:reportfraud@cesarmillaninc.com).

Your online security can be jeopardized as a result of tactics employed by third parties who try to deceive customers of legitimate commercial sites such as ours into revealing their personal information to the perpetrators for the purpose of fraud and theft. These tactics, often referred to as “phishing,” may occur through various methods. Two of the more common “phishing” methods include:

  * False or “spoofed” sites. You may receive a fraudulent email directing you to a “new” fraudulent CMI website, or you may follow a link from a third party site to a “new” fraudulent CMI website, or you may click on fraudulent entries that may appear from time to time on legitimate search engines.
  * Forged or fraudulent email. You may receive a fraudulent email that purports to have been sent by CMI or other legitimate e-commerce site. These emails seek personal information from you. These emails often pretend to “update” your account information or claim that there is an amount in dispute or use similar pretexts, all intended to induce you to divulge your personal information, particularly credit card information or your date of birth and social security number (which can be used to perpetrate identity theft).

If you suspect that you have been subjected to any of these kinds of activities, you also should contact the Federal Trade Commission at [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/ "www.ftc.gov") or phone 1-877-FTC-HELP.

### Updates to this Policy

We may occasionally modify this policy, and such modification shall be effective upon posting by us on the Site. Your continued use of this Site after such modifications will be subject to the then-current policy. We encourage you to periodically review this policy to stay informed about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact us using the following contact information:

Cesar Millan, Inc.  
PO Box 11479  
Burbank, CA 91510
